Manohar Kumar Mahato

1708/181 A'Beckett Street, Melbourne, Victoria 3000

Mobile: +61 410 983 701

Email - kumarmanohar3@gmail.com

Summary

A total experience of 9 years in the financial securities domain including 3 years in application support role and 6 years in test automation. Currently working as application support engineer in Wipro Technologies, maintaining and supporting high-availability trading platform, troubleshooting high priority and critical system issues related to application and infrastructure. Always customer focussed and go above and beyond normal routine to fix system issues. Previously, I have worked on test automation design and development using HP UFT, assisted functional testing team with automated test cases; building regression suite of scripts in Linux/Solaris environment.

Highlights

Windows Systems Networking

SQL Server Shell scripting

Perl Programming Test automation

VB Scripting HP UFT

HP ALM AWS

CCNA

Experience

Systems Analyst 01/08/2016 – Current

Client: ANZ Work Location: Sydney, Australia

- Maintenance and support of critical and high-availability trading system.
- Proactive monitoring of the applications throughout business hours.
- Prioritisation and distribution of incidents and BAU requests in queue keeping in mind the business impact and priority.
- Troubleshooting and resolving of critical issues with respect to the application, servers, databases or networks
- Problem investigation to find root cause of the applicable incidents.
- Coordination between multiple teams including internal and vendor technical support team.
- Installation of certificates and proper maintenance of the knowledge articles.
- Windows patching activities and technical verification post patching on production servers.
- Investigation of the issues related to hardware (servers, disks, or network devices) and coordination with the respective vendors to get it fixed in case of reboots or replacement of parts.
- Review and analysis of new project documents, source code, implementation plan, and disaster recovery plan for any production change as part of Change Management Process.

- Support of vendor provided applications and databases by coordinating with the respective teams following ITSM protocols and maintaining SLAs
- Decommissioning of applications, websites, servers and vendor products from data centre post project transitioning.

Key Contributions/Achievements

- Have played the role of incident recovery manager in multiple high priority incidents.
- Have fixed a high severity incident related to market data by enhancing the application logic which was not reproducible in non-production environment.
- Have fixed an ongoing overdraft issue saving the business from heavy financial loss.

Test Analyst Oct 2015 – Jul 2016

Client: ANZ Work Location: Sydney, Australia

- Automated the manual test cases using HP ALM and Selenium.
- Creation of automation regression suite for the Rebranding project.
- Requirement analysis of different modules based on project.
- Preparation of test plan, test strategy and test conditions.
- Defect tracking and maintenance.
- Analysis on test automation scope, feasibility, resourcing, planning
- Coordination between the business groups, technology groups and offshore team.
- Status reporting to various stakeholders.
- Preparation of automation test plan.
- Test automation training for the new team members.

Key Contributions/Achievements

- Worked from Sydney office interacting directly with multiple project teams at onsite.
- Have transformed an existing functional testing team into an automation team.
- Implemented a development driven testing to automate some trickier modules in an online application.

Test Analyst Apr 2013 – Sep 2015

Client: ANZ Work Location: Bangalore, India

- Automation testing using QTP Keyword driven framework
- Update to the existing automation scripts Website and various desktop applications.
- Created automation suite for Terminal application (Putty) using HP QTP
- Support for the functional testing team by providing automated test scripts
- Regression Testing
- Preparation of automation test plan
- Automation framework design and development for the Online Application webpage
- Regression testing of the Production website using selenium
- Version controlling of the test suites, test scripts etc. using SVN

Key Contributions/Achievements

Automated entire online application webpage using QTP.

Test Analyst Oct 2010 – Mar 2013

Client: Charles Schwab Work Location: Bangalore, India

- Functional testing in UNIX platform
- Automation testing using QTP Data driven framework.
- Health checks of all the test and development environments
- Regression Testing
- Pre-Regression and Post-Regression validations using Perl/Shell scripts
- Runsheet (Test Case) preparation
- Data setup for accounts and securities and performing trades and transactions as per BAU work requests
- Writing Perl/Shell scripts to automate test executions, validations and to automate other manual validations
- Version controlling of the test suites, test scripts, runsheets etc. using Clearcase

Key Contributions/Achievements

- Reduced the environment health check time to half from 1 hour to half an hour by modifying the existing scripts.
- Reduced the report validation time from 2 hours to 0.5 hours by automating using Perl script.
- Designed and developed a test automation framework using Perl for report processing team.

Certifications

Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA)

Cisco ID - CSCO13453766

AWS Certified SysOps Administrator – Associate

Validation Number - GXVHCCMKLN411M30

• AWS Certified Solutions Architect – Associate

Validation Number - B6721191BBVE15SF

Preparing for CCNP Routing and Switching certification.

Education

QUALIFICATION	SPECIALIZATION	BOARD/UNIVERSITY	Completed On	Score (Percentage/CGPA)
MS	Software Engineering	BITS-Pilani (INDIA)	May - 2015	6.62
BSc	Computer Sc. Electronics Mathematics	OSMANIA UNIVERSITY (INDIA)	Apr - 2010	77.32%
CLASS XII		CBSE (INDIA)	Apr - 2007	85.6%
Class X		CBSE (INDIA)	Apr - 2005	81.6%